ST.LOUIS,MISSOURI
圣路易斯 密苏里州
Ok.
好的
Oh!
哦!
It is notjust me,right?
并不只是因为我 对吗?
- Our girl'sgot an arm. - Yeah.
- 我们女儿手有劲了 - 对呀
Oh. Just like her dad.
哦 就像她爸爸
Look at her. We blinkedand 4 years went by.
看看她 眨眼间四年过去了
So,what do you think? Should we do this again?
那么 你怎么想? 我们要再来一次吗?
Sounds like a plan.
听起来是个计划
Uh-oh. Who's coming?Aah!
啊哦 看谁来了? 啊!
Ah.So,what doyou think,katie?
啊 那么 你的想法呢 Katie?
You want a littlebrother or sister? Yeah?Well...
想要弟弟还是妹妹? 要吗? 那好...
the boss has spoken.
老大已经开口了
Ok.Well,you go get her, and I'll go get lunch.
好了 你去找她 我去拿午餐
Ok.
好的
My daughter molly. She's 6.
我女儿Molly 六岁
She's got braids,yellow sweatshirt.
麻花辫 黄汗衫
- What am I gonna do? - Ok,ok.Calm down.
- 我该做么办? - 好的 好的 冷静一下
Braids,yellow sweatshirt.
麻花辫 黄汗衫
We were playing hideand seek up here. She must have gotten lost in the trees.
我们在这玩捉迷藏 她一定在树林里迷路了
Oh,god. I'm so stupid.
哦 上帝 我蠢透了
Tom!
Tom!
Shh,shh,shh! Wait.
嘘 嘘 嘘! 等等
Did you hear that? It came from over here.
听见了吗? 就从那儿来
Molly? Honey?!
Molly? 亲爱的?!
Daddy's here.
爸爸在这
Molly.
Molly
No.
不要
Did you find molly? Is she ok?
找到Molly了吗? 她还好吗?
Mommy,wake up. It's past 10:00.
妈妈 醒醒 已经过十点了
Ah!Damn it. Why did you let me sleep?
啊! 该死 你为什么让我睡?
Why don't you getan alarm clock?
你干吗不用闹钟?
- Did you eat? - Pizza.
- 吃饭了吗? - 匹萨
- And the baby? - Pizza.And milk.
- 宝宝呢? - 匹萨 还有牛奶
Get some sleep,jay.
去睡吧 Jay
Hey,I'll bring yousome pancakes.
嘿 我会给你带点烤薄饼
Yeah. When?
好啊 什么时候?
Hi. Want company?
嗨 要陪吗?
F.B.I. Headquarters QUANTICO,VIRGINIA
F.B.I.总部 匡迪克 弗吉尼亚
Come in.
进来
- Hi.
- 嗨
- Agent hotchner? - Yes.
- Hotchner探员吗? - 是的
I'm agentemily prentiss.
我是Emily Prentiss探员
How do you do? Oh,you're ambassadorprentiss' daughter.
你好 哦 你是Prentiss大使的女儿
I did security clearances for your mother's staff.
我为你母亲的雇员作安全认证
It was oneof my first commands.
是我最早指挥的行动之一
I believe you were off to brown at the time.
记得你毕业于布朗大学
- Actually,it was yale. - Ah.
- 事实上 是耶鲁 - 啊
I've been in the bureau almost 10 years now.
我在局里工作快十年了
Don't tell me that. Has it been that long?
别对我说那个 有那么久吗?
Apparently,sir.But I work mostly in the midwest.St.Louis,chicago.
显然是的 先生 我大多在中西部工作 圣路易斯 芝加哥
Good.
很好
- Your parents well? - Yeah,yeah,they're great.
- 你父母好吗? - 是的 他们很好
Excellent.
那好极了
What can I do for you?
有什么可以帮你?
Uh,well,I guessI was hoping you could tell mewhere to put my stuff.
呃 我希望你能告诉我 东西该放哪儿
I'm sorry?
什么?
I'm supposed to starthere today... at the bau.
我从今天起应该在这儿工作了... 在BAU
There's been a mistake.
搞错了
- I don't think so,sir. - There's definitelybeen a mistake.
- 我不这样认为 先生 - 绝对搞错了
Excuse me. We'regetting started.
- 打扰一下 - 我们要开始了
Thank you. I'll be right there.
谢谢 我就来
I didn't approve this transfer,agent prentiss.
我没有批准这份调令 Prentiss探员
I'm sorry for the confusion, but you've been misinformed.
抱歉 搞错了 但你被误传了
But--excuse me. It's very goodto see you again.
但是--失陪了 很高兴再次见到你
did you approveany transfer?
你批准调令了吗?
No. I would'vediscussed it.
没有 本来要讨论的
That's what I thought. She's got the paperworkto join the team.
- 我是这么想的 - 她有加入这个队伍的书面文件
- You want meto make a call? - No.I'll make it.
- 想让我打个电话? - 不用 我可以处理
St.Louis is in trouble.
圣路易斯有麻烦了
They've got 2 serial killers.
有两个连环杀手
This killer abducts his victims from public places,dumps them in the woods.
这个从公共场所诱拐被害人 弃尸树林
They consulted us months ago after the third murder.
他们在第三起谋杀案后向我们求援
Well,now it might beup to 6.
现在也许增加到六个了
Ellen carroll's been missing since yesterday.
Ellen Carroll昨天失踪
The first 2 victimswere found near mill creekin mark twainnational forest.
头两个被害人是在靠近米尔溪的 马克吐温国家森林发现的
No wonder it takes daysto find the bodies.
难怪要好多天才能找到尸体
The forestis 1.5 million acres and 78,000of that is wilderness.
这片树林有150万英亩 而其中的7.8万未经开采
What's the storywith these women?
其他妇女是怎么回事?
8 victims. All prostitutes. Latest is marci mitchell.
八个被害人 都是妓女 最新的那个叫Marci Mitchell
She was killed last night with a .44 magnum.
她昨晚被0.44口径的枪杀死
All are tiedto a serial shooter claiming responsibility.
有一个连环杀手声称 对所有这些负责
He's contactedjim meyers, a reporterat the missouri herald.
他联系了密苏里州前驱日报的 记者Jim Meyers
So he's not getting the attention he thinkshe deserves.
那么他是没得到自认为应得的关注
He signs itthe hollow man, names himself for the press.
他署名叫空心人 自己对新闻命名
Why hollow man? What,he feel emptyinside or something?
为什么叫空心人? 他感到内心空虚什么的吗?
He uses hollow pointbullets.
他使用中空子弹
No one even knewthis guy existed until he sentthis letter.
他送信之前 甚至都没人知道 出现了这么个假货
Well,he's killedmore victims, but lookwho he's chosen.
他杀的人更多了 但看看他选择的对象
Hundreds of victimsgo unnoticed because they'resocial outcastsand never makethe front page.
没有注意到那么多被害人 是因为她们是从未被社会重视的被遗弃者
When mill creek kills,the hollow man shoots another prostitute.
磨溪杀手杀人时 这个空心人枪击了另一个妓女
So one doesn't want to be outdone by the other.
就是一个不想被另一个超越
Sounds likesibling rivalry to me.
我听上去就像兄弟竞争
They've been killing independently of eachother for a year now.
他们一年来都是独立行凶
Each kill they'relearning something...
各自都在学习...
from the other.
从对方身上
No Woman is Safe
没有女人是安全的
Elbert hubbert once wrote,"if men could only know each other,they would neitheridolize nor hate."
埃尔伯特・哈伯特曾说 "男人如果相互了解 他们既不会崇拜也不会怨恨"
Thank you.
谢谢你
What's wrong?
怎么了?
Did you know there areroughly 30 serial killers at large in the U.S.At any given time?
你知道吗 美国一直以来 大约有30个连环杀手在逃?
It's an incredibly rare occurrence to have themoperating in the same city.
同时出现在一个城市犯案 这简直难以置信 太罕见了
- How many timeshas that happened? - To my knowledge,3 times.
- 有过几次? - 就我所知 三次
There was a guy killing at the same time as the son of sam.
一个跟山姆之子同时行凶
And then againin new orleans, and most recentlywith the phoenix murders.
还有一次在新奥尔良 最近的一次是菲尼克斯凶杀案
Serial shootersare typically loners.
连环杀手都是典型的孤独者
This guy likesto kill at night.
喜欢在夜间行凶
His victimsare prostitutes,so he may lack confidence with womenor have poorsocial skills.
他的对象是妓女 那么也许是 自己应对女人缺乏自信或者缺少社交技巧
No rape. The guycould be impotent.
没有强暴 可能有生理缺陷
He's a wannabetough guy.
他想成为个硬汉
It's not hard to be  tough holding a .44.
拿着把0.44口径手枪一点都不像硬汉
The gun gives him power and lets him maintaindistance from the kill.
枪给了他力量 让他维持远距离杀人
This guy doesn'twant to touch the bodieswith his hands.
他不想用自己的手接触尸体
Mill creek killer.
磨溪杀手
Hunts during the day, targets educated,middle-class women.
日间行凶 目标都是 受过教育的中产阶级妇女
He'd have to lookand act like they do.
他需要观察 还要表现得跟他们一样
The women die from blunt force head traumas.
这些女人死于钝器造成的头部外伤
This guy wantsto be close, he wants to feel the lifeleave their bodies.
这个人喜欢近距离 想体验生命逝去的过程
These guysare polar opposites.
他们截然相反
Just like their victims.They live in the samecity but they'reworlds apart.
就像他们的被害人 住在同一个城市却生活在两个世界
I'm gonna see ifthe shooter's victims have any familiesI can talk to.
我看看枪手的被害人有没有家属 我可以跟他们谈谈
That's a good idea.I'm already familiar with the mill creek case.
好主意 我已经熟悉了磨溪杀手的案子
Reid,can you takea look at the letter for handwriting analysisand psycho linguistics?
Reid 你能不能看看信件 做一下笔迹鉴定和心理语言学分析?
- Of course. - Looks like I'm with you.
- 当然 - 看来我要跟着你了
I'll go aheadand talk with ellencarroll's husband.
我去跟Ellen Carroll的丈夫谈谈
I'm meeting jim meyers, the reporterfrom the missouri herald.
我去见那个记者Jim Meyers
Well,tell him not to write about the hollow man.
告诉他不要报道空心人
If we want to drawthe shooter out, best way to do that isto act like he doesn't exist.
如果要揪出这个枪手 最好的办法就是装作他不存在
I'd feel much betterwhen you find ellen.
你们找到Ellen 我就能感觉好点
Mr. Carroll,believe me,we are trying.
Carroll先生 相信我 我们在努力
You know,when you have kids,you become so fixated on where they areand what they're doing,
知道吗 一旦有了孩子 你会变得太过在意他们的行踪的活动
you don't thinkyou need  to worryabout your spouse.
会觉得没必要去担心另一半
I understandyour wife is a partnerat a law firm.
我了解你妻子是律师事务所的合伙人
Now aside from work,taking care of the family, does she make timefor herself?
那么除了工作 照顾家里 她有自己的业余时间吗?
She's an avid runner,participates in the st.Louis marathonevery year.
她很迷恋跑步 每年都参加圣路易斯的马拉松比赛
Is she shy,nervous about meeting new people?
她认识陌生人时 会感到害羞 紧张吗?
Ever since we had katie, I'd say she'smuch more trusting.
自从有了Katie之后 我就说她更愿意相信别人了
You don't rememberher talking to anyone you don't knowat that playground?
你真的不记得她在广场上和陌生人说过话吗?
No. No one.
没 没有
How did I not seesomeone take my wife?
我怎么可能看不见有人绑走了我妻子?
Mr. Carroll,the man who did this, somehow he justfits right in.
Carroll先生 干这个的男人 不知何故他就是很适合那里
He doesn't look or sound like he doesn't belong.
他表现得很像
Oh,hey,little lady.
哦 嘿 小女士
Hey.
嗨
She keeps asking me, when her mommy'scoming home.
她不停地问我 妈妈什么时候回家
I don't knowwhat to saY.
我不知道该怎么回答
I missed you.
我想你
You are so beautiful.
你真美
Agents hotchnerand reid,fbi.
Hotchner和Reid探员 FBI的
- What do you want? - We'd like to talk to you.
- 想干嘛? - 我们要跟你谈谈
Hold thatbadge up again.
再把证件拿来看看
We're here to talk to you about marcie mitchell.
我们来跟你谈谈Marcie Mitchell
- I'm her mother. - I'm sorryfor your loss,ma'am.
- 我是她妈妈 - 你痛失爱女 我很遗憾 女士
What's this?
这怎么了?
They're for me. Take your brother inside.
他们是来找我的 带弟弟到里面去
- Is this about mom? - I said inside.
- 跟妈妈有关吗? - 我说了进去
You gonna judge meor ask questions?
你们来这是评论我还是问问题
Is there anyone who can help youwith the kids?
有人能帮你照顾孩子吗?
Is that whatyou came here for?
这是你们来的目的?
Ma'am,we'vejust been assigned your daughter's case.
女士 我们刚接手你女儿的案子
We're in the processof gathering information, but so far no witnesseshave come forward.
正在收集信息 但目前为止 没有自告奋勇的目击证人
Well,around here guns go off like those damn car alarms--every 15 minutes.
这附近枪声就象这该死的汽车喇叭-- 十五分钟一次
Nobody'sstupid enough to talk, nobody cares.
没人会傻到去说 根本没人在意
We do.
我们在意
You wouldn't even behere if it wasn't for them.
如果不是为了她们 你们压根不会来
"Heinous crimes against upstanding membersof the community."
"对抗上层社会的极恶罪行"
Nobody writes about prostitutes being shot
根本没人报道妓女被枪击
because they won'tadmit they think they'recleaning up the place.
因为没人会承认 他们认为这是扫清这一地区的行为
You're right.
你说的对
Caseslike your daughter's usually go unsolved.
像你女儿的案子经常不了了之
The problem is peoplearen't looking for them because they don't knowthat they're missing.
问题是人们都不知道她们失踪了 所以没人会去寻找
Part of her job was to stay below the radar.
她工作的一部分就是不被注意
Doesn't mean she wasany less important.
但这并不意味着她就不重要
She made bad choices.
她做了糟糕的选择
But she was a good person.
但她是好人
She loved those boys.
她爱这些孩子
Whoever shot her should pay for what they did.
杀她的人应该付出代价
So don't come in here and say you're sorry.
那么别只是走进来 轻巧地说一句遗憾
Just dosomething about it.
拿出行动来
We will,Ma'am.
我们会的 女士
Hi. You must beagent sheridan?
嗨 你一定是Sheridan探员?
- Agent jareau. - Hi.
- Jareau探员 - 嗨
- Really appreciateyou coming so quickly. - Yeah.
- 很感激你们能那么快赶来 - 应该的
Why don't youset up in here?
不如就放在这里吧?
Oh,wow.You've gotlots of evidence for the mill creekkiller case.
哦 哇 关于磨溪杀手的案子 你们收集了好多证据啊
- What aboutthe hollow man? - Right here.
- 那么空心人呢? - 在这儿
There's beenat least 8 women shot. This is all we've got?
至少有八个女人被杀了 就只有这些?
You know thesecases don't generate much evidence.
你知道的 这类案子不会有很多证据
All we have at the scene are a couple of bulletsand no one's talking.
我们就只有现场的几颗弹头 没人愿意说
Well,hopefully,we can change that.
希望我们可以改变这个情况
Agent jareau,there's a reporter here to see you.
Jareau探员 有个记者来找你
- Thank you.Excuse me. - Sure.
- 谢谢你 失陪 - 请便
Jim meyers.Hi.Agent jareau. We spoke on the phone.
Jim Meyers 嗨 我是Jareau探员 我们通过电话
Hi. Thanks for stopping by.
- 嗨 - 谢谢你能过来
Sure. Here's thatletter I faxed to you.
当然的 这是我传给你的那封信
Oh,great.
哦 好极了
So,did the hollow manshoot those prostitutes because I wrote aboutthe mill creek victims?
那么 空心人枪杀了那些妓女 是由于我报道磨溪杀手遇害者的缘故吗?
He would've killedthem anyway.
他无论怎样都会杀他们的
But right now he'slooking for recognition. That's whyhe's contacted you.
但现在他正寻求关注 所以他联系了你
But I'm not in any danger.
但我没有面临危险吧
I mean,I don't wantto be staring downthe barrel of a gun.
我的意思是 我可不想对准枪口
Right now he needs you.You're his only hope toget on that front page.
现在他需要你 你是让他上头版的唯一希望
You know,I had no ideaI could get on a serial killer's radarby writing aboutanother one.
我并不知道会因为报道一个连环杀手 而让另一个注意到
We're going to ask thatyou not print anything relatingto the hollow man orthe women he's killed.
我们要请你停止报道任何 有关空心人的消息 包括被杀的女人
Don't those victimsdeserve just as much inkas those other women?
跟其他女人相比 这些被害人 难道连相同的墨水都不该得到吗?
Of course they do.
当然应该
But we needthe shooter to keep communicatingwith you.
但我们需要枪手与你保持联系
And if you satisfyhis need for attention, he could disappear,and I'm sorry.
而如果他想被关注的需求得以满足 可能就会消失 我很抱歉
We just can't takethat chance.
但我们不能冒这个险
Excuse me,agent jareau?
打扰一下 Jareau探员?
We just found ellencarroll's body.
我们刚找到了Ellen Carroll的尸体
Agents gideon,morgan,this is agent sheridan.
Gideon和Morgan探员 这位是Sheridan探员
- How are you? - Forgive me.
你好 请原谅
How faris the abduction itefrom these woods?
诱拐地离这片树林有多远?
About 40 miles or so.
大约40英里
He tried to hide itpretty well. He covers the bodyvery carefully.
- 他将尸体藏得很隐蔽 - 他掩埋地非常小心
Must feel remorsefor killing them.
肯定在为杀了他们感到自责
This lipstick's beenapplied recently. It's still moist.
口红是最近才用的 还是湿的
Look at her hair. It's been brushed,put behind her ears.
看她的头发 梳理过 还整齐地放至耳后
She was abducted,what,an hour from here? Draggedthrough these woods?
她不是在离这一小时车程的地方被拐 拖进树林的吗?
Her hair would notlook like that.
她的头发不应该这样
So he keeps her safefrom the elements and then comes backfor the body.
那么是他保护她不被自然因素伤到 然后可以回来看尸体
That's why he chooses a secondary locationthat's so remote.
因此他选择那么远的地方弃尸
- This isn'tabout remorse. - No.
- 这不是后悔 - 不是
- He wantsto be alone with her. - Needs his privacy.
他想单独跟她在一起 想保护自己的隐私
You never noticed the hair or the makeupbefore?
以前从没注意过头发和妆容吗?
No. Maybe it wasthe timing.
没有 也许是时间的关系
She was foundwithin 24 hours,and the others had alreadysuccumbed to the elements.
她在24小时内就被找到了 其他人已经腐烂了
Sex actswith dead bodies are rare occurrences.
跟死人的性行为是非常少见的
However,bundy did it regularly.
然而 这个杀手做得很有规律
So how is thisgoing to help usto catch him?
那么这对我们抓住他有什么帮助?
Now we knowhe has a ritual. He needs to defilethe bodies.
我们知道了他有个仪式 需要亵渎尸体
Next timewe'll be herewaiting for him.
下次我们就在这等他
Sixth Victim Falls to Mill Creek Killer
六名被害人丧身于磨溪杀手
We're off-duty just like you.
我们跟你一样 都下班了
2 victims at once. That's a first for him.
一次两名被害人 他第一次这么干
You think he wentout looking to kill more than one woman,or is it just happenstance?
你们觉得他打算好要多杀一个的 还是碰巧的?
He chose a differenthunting ground.
他更换了杀人场所
Yes,we're in an alley,but we're behind an expensive hotelin a nice neighborhood.
没错 我们是在巷子里 但是在高级小区里的高档旅馆后面
You get a differentclass of prostitute, ones that don't walkthe street alone.
妓女的层次也不一样了 她们不会独自上街
He was lookingfor a challenge.
他在寻求挑战
Question is,what gavehim the confidence to stray outof his comfort zone?
问题是 他哪儿来的信心 走出他的安全地带
Make sure to runthat for prints.
确保做一下指纹鉴定
He displayed the newspaperbetween them.
将报纸展示在她们中间
He took the time when he could've just tossed it aside.
原可以只是扔在一边的 他却花时间处理
It's deliberatE. He wants us to knowhe's angry.
明显是有预谋的 想让我们知道他在愤怒
Angry enoughto change his M.O.
愤怒到改变作案手法
I heard there was a double homicide this morning.
我听说早上发生了一起双尸案
Was it hollow man?
是不是空心人干的?
- Agents are confirmingthat now. - I've written about him.
- 警方正在确认 - 我应该报道他的
There's no guaranteethat he would've stopped killingif you would've giveninto his demands.
就算你写了他的报道 也不保证他就金盆洗手
In fact,media attention could've fueled himto kill more.
媒体的介入甚至可能激发他更多的杀意
We don't knowthat for sure.
但我们也不肯定呀
This is all justa guessing game,isn't it?
你们只是在猜测，对吗?
No. It's behavioralanalysis.
不 这是行为分析
We're dealingwith an offenderwho believes that murdering peopleis a good wayto become famous.
我们正在打交道的这个人 相信杀人可以一举成名
All I know is thatyou told me to ignore himand he takes 2 lives.
我只知道 你叫我故意忽略他 代价是两条人命
If I dismissthis double homicide, what happens tomorrow?
如果我不理会这起双尸案 明天又会发生什么？
We won't knowuntil then.
那要到时再看了
Too bad we couldn'ttrace any printsfrom the newspaper.
很糟糕 报纸上找不到任何指纹
What have you got?
你有什么发现?
he only sent thisto an individual,
他把信寄给单独的个体
which shows he'snot confident enough to initiate contactwith the masses.
说明他还怯于联系大众传媒
Emotional indicators are analyzed through slants.
字体倾斜方式可推导出情续特征
The shootermaintains vertical, narrow-lettered writing,both signs of repression.
凶手的字迹垂直削瘦 显示出抑郁倾向
And the pressure,if you look closely, is excessively heavy,
仔细看还可发现 笔力特别重
which showsthat he's uptight and caneasily overreact.
说明他情绪紧张 容易反映过度
You got all thatfrom his handwriting?
都是从笔迹中看出来的?
Graphology is an effectiveand reliable indicatorof personality and behavior.
笔迹能有效而准确地告诉我们 书写者的个性和行为模式
My writing'salways different.
我的笔迹一直在变
That's because itexpresses your emotionsat that given time,
因为它承载了你当时的情绪
just likeyour facial expressionsparallel the wayyou're feeling whileyou're speaking.
就像你的面部表情和 你说话时的情绪是一致的
I'm surprised this guywrites in cursive.
我倒没想到那人写的是草书
His message is so clear. I would've thoughthe'd print everything.
他传递的信息那么清楚 还以为他会把什么都打印出来呢
Actually,his connectedwriting shows that he deals with problemsin a practicaland direct manner.
事实上 连贯书写的方式说明 他处理问题的方式向来实用直接
- Like shooting someone. - Exactly.
- 比如用枪射人 - 没错
The hollow manuses simple statements, all first person.
空心人使用简单陈述句 都为第一人称
For example,"I won't be ignored."
比如 "我再不能被忽略"
He's obviously tiredof feeling this way.
显然已经厌倦了被人忽视
It's quite possible he'sgot a job in solitude or one that he feelsstrips him of his identity.
很可能他的工作寂寂无名 或令他感到逐渐失去自我
His job might require himto wear a uniform, something that showsabsolutely no individuality.
可能工作要求他身着制服 这就完全抹消了个体意识
Or he may be overqualified for his menial job
或者他觉得自己大材小用
and feels that he doesn't get the respectthat he necessarilydeserves.
没有得到应有的敬意
But todayhe's killed 2 women, which tells ushe's growing confident.
但今天他杀了两位女子 说明自信心渐涨
This makes himunpredictable and dangerous.
导致他更加危险 更难预测
And because he hasno physical contactwith his victims,
由于他和受害人没有肢体接触
it's going to make himthat much harder to catch.
抓他落网难度会更大
We have more informationon the mill creek killer
磨溪杀手一案有更多的线索
because he spendsa lot of timewith his victimsbefore and afterhis kills.
是因为他在案前案后 与被害人相处甚久
Because his victimswillingly follow him in broad daylight,he appears harmless.
被害人在光天化日之下自愿随他离开 说明他外表相当无害
- He's mostlikely handsome. - Handsome?
- 可能还很英俊 - 英俊?
Yes.These women wouldn't follow an unattractive man.They just wouldn'T.
对 这些女人不会跟着一个 毫无吸引力的男人走 人之常情么
He's handsome,and he's got the socialskills to trick his victims.
他外貌英俊 拥有追踪受害人的技巧
Those who know him well,they'd be shocked to learn that he'sthe man that we're after.
认识他的人 绝对想不到 他就是我们锁定的目标
He's been ableto get his victims awayfrom family,friends.
他能够使受害人离开她们的家人朋友
Obviously,this makeshim feel powerful.
显然他为此而感到强势
If this guy is so smart,why would he risk driving his victimsfrom the abduction siteto the woods?
如果这人真那么聪明 为什么又冒险把受害人从绑架地点转移到林中？
Because of the ritual.
因为仪式
It's become the mostimportant thing to him.
这对他而言极为重要
Dominates his thoughts. Bullets providethe privacy he needs.
掌控了他的思维 子弹提供了他所需的私密感
The hollow manis motivated byexternal pressures.
空心人的动机是内心的压力
This is a guy who simplywants attention.
他只想成名
The mill creek killer,on the other hand, he's drivenby internal forces.
而磨溪杀手 却为内心张力而驱动
He's a sexuallymotivated offender.
一个为性所驱的侵犯者
Now,this makes hima lot more predictable
因此其行为更容易预料
but don't think for a second it makes himany easier to catch.
但别以为这等于 能轻松地将他抓获
Where are you?
你在哪儿?
Excuse mE.
打扰一下
Meredith dale. 25.
Meredith Dale 25岁
She was supposedto meet her friend for a bike ridebut disappeared.
骑车结束后她没有和朋友汇合 她失踪了
- Disappeared when? - An hour ago.
- 什么时候? - 一小时前
- How can we be sureit's him? - Well,look at her.
- 怎么肯定是他干的? - 看看她
She's his type physically, she vanishes into thin air.
体型符合他的口味 就这么突然失踪了
It's got the mill creek'sM.O.All over it.
一看就是磨溪杀手的作案手法
I'll set up road blocks in and out of the forest.
我会在树林内外设置路障
Well,based onthe other timelines, we have to assume he's hidingher body right now.
根据时间轴 我们估计他现在正在藏尸
Best chanceof catching himis find meredith dale's bodyand sit tight.
抓他的最佳时机是找到Meredith Dale的尸体 守株待兔
We know he'll be back.
他会回来的
I'm going to need you to step out of your vehicle.
请走出到车外
- What's going onhere,officer? - Just routine check.
- 怎么了 警官? - 例行检查
- Can you open your back? - Uh,yeah,sure.
- 能打开后备箱吗? - 呃 当然
Many people come throughhere today?
今天你们一直守在这?
- What are youdoing up here? - Went for a hike.
- 你来做什么? - 远足
No water,no supplies?
没带水和供给?
My bootsare all I need.
只要一双靴子就够了
That it?
行了?
- That's it. - Ok.
- 行了 - 好
What if these dumpsitesaren't random?
如果弃尸地点并非随意选取 又如何？
The bodies werescattered all over.
尸体到处都是
Look at this. There's no pattern.
看看 根本没有固定模式
No,I see that,but we're talking about a lotof area to cover here.
这我知道 现在问题是 有很大一块区域需要准备
He had to havesome kind of plan going into these woods.
去树林前他总得有什么计划吧
Must have done his homework.
一定做过功课
Ok.The first bodywas found deep into the woods.
好 第一具在树林深处被发现
That's a 3-hour carride from the city.
离城市有三个小时的车程
The first time,he's more carefulin disposing of her.
一开始 他弃尸时很小心
Her body was discovered by a forest ranger5 daysafter the abduction.
绑架五天后 尸体才被守林人发现
And all the other victims--look at this¡ª they followthe same pattern.
而其他的受害人-- 看 都遵循同一个模式
What are you saying? You think he worksup there?
你的意思是 他在那边工作?
He might.
有可能
All I doknow for sureis that he has to be familiar enoughwith these woods
但我肯定他对树林非常熟悉
to know when a rangeris on duty.
知道守林人的作息表
He knew preciselywhen and where to drop the bodies.
知道弃尸的恰当时间和地点
Now that is an awesome place to dump a person.
这地方用来弃尸 真是太完美不过了
- Come on,garcia. - What?I'm justsaying,angel fish.
- 拜托 Garcia - 哈? 我开玩笑的啦 神仙鱼
A million acresconverts into over 2,300square miles to cover.
一百万亩地 也就是2300平方公里的地方啊
Evil knewwhat he was doing.
鬼才知道他在干啥
Yeah?Well,now so do we.
啊？我们也该知道
Talk to me. How's the rangerschedule break down?
说说看 守林人的作息怎么安排的?
Ok.The national forestis divided into 6 ranger districts,
这片国家森林分为6大区
which are patrolledevery 3 to 5 days.
每隔3至5天进行一次巡逻
Now,the potosi-fredricktown area must be where he'sheaded to next
他下个目的地肯定是 珀多西-费得瑞克镇
because the rangers werejust there yesterday,
因为昨天守林人才去过
which means they're notscheduled to revisit itfor at leastanother 3 days.
说明至少后三天他们不会再去
And look at that, it's the district closest to the city.
看看 这是离市区最近的林区
Well,that makes sense. He's in a hurry.
有道理 说明他很着急
He wantsto get in and out of there without a lot of trouble.
不想在进出上多费时费力
Which area has the easiest access to the main road?
那块区域和主干道交通最方便?
That would be... saltgrass cove.
应该是...盐草湾
Saltgrass cove.
盐草湾
Yep.He'd have plentyof time to revisit her.
恩 他有足够的时间再回去 拜访她
What?No,no.I don't want to know that.Bye-bye.
啥? 不不 我不想知道 拜拜
Think I know where he took meredith dale.
我知道他把Meredith Dale放哪儿了
Brownie,come here.
Brownie 过来
Damn it.
混球
Please,please.
喂 喂
Everything needsto look the sameas when he left it.
每处细节都要原封不动
- He'll come back. - He needs to seemeredith again.
- 他会回来的 - 他需要再看到Meredith
This bastard has killed 7 women on my watch.
这个混蛋已经在我眼皮底下杀了7个女人
- Comb the scene! - Oh,no.Please,please!Stop!
- 仔细搜查现场! - 不 不行 请停下!
Let's clearthe immediate area.
立即清空这片地区
Post yourselvesalong the perimeter. It's imperativethat you become invisible.
沿边界布防 严禁任何人显露行藏
He set his own trap.
他作茧自缚
What we need to do now is stake out in the woodsand hunt him,
当务之急 就是隐身林中 螳螂捕蝉 黄雀在后
just like he doeshis victims.
正如他对受害人所做
That's got to be him.
应该是他
Fbi!Stay down! Hands whereI can see them.
FBI! 蹲下! 把手放我能看到的地方！
Ok,ok. Just take it easy.
稳住 稳住
Jim meyers. What the hell?
Jim Meyers 怎么是你
- You'rethe mill creek killer? - What?No.
- 你就是磨溪杀手? - 什么? 当然不是
Then how the helldid you get here?
那你怎么知道来这儿?
I got another letter from the hollow man.
我从空心人那儿得到了另外一封信
Telling you exactly where to findmeredith dale?
告诉你找到Meredith Dale的确切藏尸地?
I swear. You can read it.
我发誓 你们可以读信
"Follow the cottonwood trail throughsaltgrass cove."
"沿杨木林直到盐草湾"
Wait a minute. We just figuredthis out ourselves.
等等 我们也才发现
How can another killerknow the specificsabout someone else'sdumpsite?
另一个杀手从何得知确切的弃尸地点？
What's going on?
出什么事了?
It's going to beall over the news.
新闻将会铺天盖地
Looklikethe hollow man didn't give youthe exclusive this time.
看来这回空心人可没给你独家
So our plan to catchthe mill creek killer was ruinedby the hollow man?
所以我们抓磨溪杀手的计划被空心人给搅了?
And now the hollow man'son a high.
现在空心人肯定很兴奋
He hasn't pulledthe trigger since he took2 victims yesterday.
自从昨天他杀了两个人 还没扣过扳机呢
Is he satisfied or is he just getting started?
他已经得到了满足 还是一切才刚开始?
We'll find out.
会找到答案的
"Hollow man helps fbifind the mill creekkiller's victim."
"空心人帮助联邦调查局 寻获磨溪杀手的受害人"
Nice.He's alerted the media and injected himselfinto the investigation.
真不错 他不但通知了媒体 还把自己弄进调查中
He's getting the attentionhe's been craving.
他成名的欲望更强烈了
But if the shooterreally wants to getthe other guy arrested,
可是如果他想要叫磨溪杀手被抓住
he would've called usand not the media.
应该联系我们而非媒体
He must knowthe mill creek killer needsto revisit the body.
他一定知道磨溪杀手 会重新去找尸体
If he can't defilethe woman again,the need'll become so strong,it could pushhim into a frenzy.
如果他无法再次亵渎受害人 这种需求会不断增强 使他疯狂
And if that happens,this guy is just a time bombwaiting to explode.
如果真是这样 这家伙就是个定时炸弹
Excuse me.
不好意思
Hi. Look,I'm having a day.
呃 我今天特别不顺
My car won't startand I forgot my phone.
车发动不起来 手机也忘带了
Could I use yoursto make a call?
能借你的用一下吗?
Yeah. Ok.I know it's here. I just used it.
好的 等一下 刚才我还用过呢
What,you know what? Forget the phone.
呃 算了 不用找了
Maybe it'll start for you.
也许你能帮我发动车
Walk with me. It's rightaround the corner.
跟我走吧 就在对角
- No,that's ok. - No,come on.
- 没关系 - 不 来吧
No. No!
不 不要！
- Walk with me. - Let go of me!
- 跟我走 - 放开我!
- Now! - Let me go!
- 马上!
Help!
救命! 救命!
Somebody! Somebody!Help,please!
有人吗! 有人吗! 救命啊！
Please!
有人吗 救命！
- At first he seemedso normal. - Was he handsome?
- 刚开始他挺正常的 - 他帅吗?
- Excuse me?
- 什么? - 他长得帅吗?
Yeah. He was.
是的
Actually,that'swhy I stopped.
所以 我才停下的
When didhis demeanor change?
他什么时候态度转变了?
After I refusedto go to his car.
我不愿意跟他一起去车上
He grabbedmy arm so hard I thought thatit would break.
他用力地抓着我手臂 感觉要断了
I've been watching the newsabout all these women being abducted,and I just started screaming.
我看过新闻里那些被绑走的女子 所以开始大叫
You trustedyour instincts.
你跟随了自己的直觉
Because of that,you're still alive.
所以保全了性命
Miss,there's a sketch artist here with us.
小姐 这里有一位素描画像师
He can create a prettyaccurate rendition from your descriptionof this man.
能通过你的描述逼真地画出那人的面貌
- Would you sit with him? - Absolutely.
- 可以和他谈一下吗? - 当然
officer.
警官
- I'm glad you're all right. - Thank you.
- 很高兴你平安无事 - 谢谢
Well,he's becoming irrational and violentin public.
他开始失去理智 在公众场合作案了
That's exactlywhat the hollow man wanted him to do.
正合了空心人的愿
Well,if he doesn'tfind a victim soon, he'll becomemore dangerous.
如果他还找不到下一个受害人 就会变得更加危险
How's that possible?
怎么说?
He'll dropthe ruse entirely and just startgrabbing women at random.
他会完全弃计划于不顾 随便找个女人下手
Great. Thanks,man.
好的 谢了
The witness gota good look at themill creek killer.
证人把磨溪杀手看得很清楚
You know,if it'sthe hollow man's intentionto force himinto a frenzy,
如果空心人想要把磨溪杀手逼疯
he's getting what he wants.
他已经得偿所愿
He knew exactly where to find meredith dale's body.
他清楚地知道Meredith Dale尸体的位置
He figured out the route to the dumpsitethe same way we did.
他和我们一样 找出了弃尸点的规律
They always sayserial killers makethe best profilers.
人们都说连续杀人狂 是最好的侧写观摩对象
Yeah,butthis guy's dead-on.
对 但这个家伙丧心病狂
Yeah.The headline doesn't mention the shooter at all.
报刊头条根本没提枪击犯的存在
We talked to jim meyers,the reporter, asked him not to respondto the letter,
我们说服了Jim Meyers 那个记者 要他不去理会空心人的信
he doesn't,and thenthe guy goes out andshoots 2 more women.
他答应了 那人就出去杀了两个女人
- In a betterpart of town. - What gives himthis confidence?
- 还在更上流的地方 - 他哪来的自信心?
What's the significance of the paper at the scene?
案发现场的报纸又有什么意义?
We know he wantsto be newsworthy. He could've justtossed it aside.
他想让此事具有新闻价值 只要把报纸扔下即可
Instead,he displayed it.
他却特地摆了出来
There's somethinghe wants us to look at. There's definitelysomething in the paper.
他想让我们看什么东西 报纸里一定有什么线索
I thinkI figured it out.
我想我找到了
What is it?
是什么?
They're talking. In the classifieds.
他们在交谈 通过分栏广告
classifieds,code names. This feels likean old spy movie.
分栏广告 代号 搞得像个过时的间谍片
It's low-tech,simple,but very effective.
技术含量是低 但简单有效
They've beendoing this for months, and nobody ever knew it.
他们干了几个月了 但谁也没发现
This is the first onethat I found. The references arewhat made me suspicious.
这是我找到的第一条 内容令人起疑
"Sunny,are you an artist too?
"Sunny 你也是个艺术家吗?
I'd love to see your work sometime.Holden."
希望有机会见识你的作品 Holden"
Sunny? Holden?
Sunny? Holden?
They're charactersfrom catcher in the rye.
都是《麦田里的守望者》中的角色
Widely acceptedas a loved bookof sociopaths.
广泛被反社会者接纳的书
Mark david chapman quoted it after killing john lennon.
Mark David Chapman在杀害约翰・列农后 引用了此书
Deranged minds identifywith holden's alienationand detachment.
疯狂的头脑与Holden的 冷漠孤僻符合
I found the initial contact. It ran in the paperunchanged for months.
我找到了最初的联系 在报纸上一成不变的登了好几个月
"We have differenttastes, but I can appreciate your art.Sunny."
"我们品位迥异 但我欣赏你的艺术 Sunny."
Sunny's the hollow man. He initiated contact.
Sunny就是空心人 是他启动了交流
- What's he gettingout of it? - A mentor.
- 他有啥好处? - 导师
Offered admirationand respect.
当他付出欣赏和尊敬
In return,he gains encouragementand confidence.
做为回报 他得到了鼓励和信心
But when the hollow manremained unnoticedby the press,
但是当空心人始终不被媒体关注
he resented his mentor and turned itinto a rivalry.
他开始憎恨自己的导师 并展开了杀人竞争
Hollow man became jealous.
空心人开始嫉妒了
They were both killers,but they weren't seen in the same playing field.
他们都是杀手 却不能出现在同一个赛场上
What else did you find?
你还有什么发现?
"An overwhelming area and you never get lost?"
"一个绝好的地方 你永远不会迷路?"
Then the answerto this question.
然后是答案
"I do my research." It's not so randomwhen you know the area.
"我做了研究 如果你了解了就会知道这不是随便挑的"
I like cotton woodin sgc."
"我喜欢SGC的Cotton Wood"
Sgc?He's talking aboutsaltgrass cove.
SGC? 他是说盐草湾?
- He told him howto find meredith dale. - Why?
- 他告诉他怎么找到Meredith Dale - 为什么
Teaching his studenta lesson.
给学生上课
We understandtheir relationship.
我们了解他们之间的关系
Let's use itagainst them.
让我们利用这点
Hey,sweetness.Make me smile and tell meyou got a name.
嗨 甜甜 让我笑笑 告诉我你有名字了
Oh,I got scadsof them,babe, but none paid for thesepersonal ads.
我查到了很多 宝贝 但没有这些个人广告付费的信息
They went with cash, totally old school.
他们付现金 真是守旧
I hate itwhen they're smart. 2 separate accountsin good standing.
他们这么狡猾真让我头疼 两个信誉良好的账户
Well,these guysare good. Thanks.
他们很不错 谢谢
Garcia saysthey coveredtheir tracks. How's it goingin here?
Garcia说他们掩盖了踪迹 现在情况怎么样?
Reid's imitatingthe hollow man'slanguage patterns to send a messageto the mill creek killer.
Reid在模仿空心人的语气给磨溪杀手发消息
He's offering condolenceson losing meredith dale.
他正对失去Meredith Dale表示哀悼
Well,if he can'tget to meredith dale, he's gonna needa body.
如果他不能得到Mredith Dale 他就会要一具尸体
He's gonnaneed it real soon.
很快就要
You guys worriedthat the hollow man's going to ruinour plan again?
你们担心空心人会毁了我们的计划?
He wants the mill creek killer to get caught.
他希望磨溪杀手被抓住
The pupil's tryingto kill the teacher?
学生想杀掉老师?
Hope you're close,reid.
希望你快了 Reid
You got less than an hour to meet the deadline.
还有不到一小时就是最后期限了
You'll be surrounded.
我们就在周围
Need you to relax... as best you can.
尽量放松点
This guy's going to wantto get close to you, and he's goingto want to examine you.
这人会想接近你 而且会想检查你
He's going to wantto touch me?
他还打算摸我吗?
Since you're a gift,not a marked victim, he might tryto make you his own.
因为你是个礼物 不是标记的受害者 他可能希望拥有你
But we're not going to let him get that far.
但我们不会让他做的这么过份
We need him to getclose to confirmhe's the killer.
我们只需要他近得可以确认是杀手
There's nothing normal about this guy.Nothing.
这家伙不正常 完全不正常
You have any questions?
你有问题吗?
Let's do this.
就这样吧
Ok. Down you go.
好吧 躺下
Close your eyes. Try to relax.
闭上眼睛 试着放松
What do you think? Did it sound likethe hollow man?
你们怎么想? 听上去像空心人吗?
Hopefully the mill creekkiller will buy it.
希望磨溪杀手能上当
"Dear holden,they say imitation" is the highest formof flattery.
"亲爱的Holden 他们说模仿是最好的恭维"
"Since you were almostin harm's way, "I thought I'd sharesome art.
"因为你使用比较危险的方法 我觉得我可以跟你分享一些技艺"
Should make youfeel better. here's my gift to you.sunny.
那会让你感觉更好 这就是我给你的礼物 Sunny"
Hello.
你好
Fbi! Get down!Stay down!
FBI! 趴下!趴着!
One down,one to go.
抓了一个 还差一个
Stop right here.
在这停下
It's going to betough to pushthrough this crowd.
想挤过人群不太容易
That's the idea.
这是计划中的
I'm getting out. Securea path to the door.
我出去 开一条路
Everyone,take a step back. Get back!
请大家退后一步 退后!
What do you have to sayto the families of the women you killed?
你打算向受害者家人说什么?
Do you have any remorse for what you've done?
你对你的所做所为没有一丝懊悔?
- You're going to hell. - You deserve to die!
- 去死吧 - 你该死!
I've alertedall news outletsthat we'll be holdinga press conferencein 10 minutes.
我已经通告所有媒体 我们会在10分钟内开一个发布会
- And you havethe script? - Right here.
- 你有发言稿了吗? - 在这
Be sure to sayexactly those words.
一定要说那些话
- The wording'simportant,jj. - Relax.
- 那些话很重要 JJ - 放松点
It's notmy first party,boys.
这对我不是头一回了 小男生
Gideon,we don't havemuch on mill creek, especially if he sayshe stumbled on the body.
Gideon我们没有太多麽溪杀手的证据 特别是如果他说她是假扮尸体
So what arewe going to do?
那我们该怎么做?
I'll go tryand do my job.
我会做好我的事
Ok. Thanks.
好的 多谢
You comfortable?
舒服吗?
As comfortable as anyonecan be in handcuffs.
跟所有戴手铐的人一样舒服
Let me see.
让我看看
I'm jason gideon.
我是Jason Gideon
You know,I don'tknow your name or where you're from...
我不知道你的名字 也不知道你来自哪里
the only thingwe do knowis you'rean intelligent,good-looking man
我们唯一知道的事是 你很是个又聪明又好看的男人
with an inflated ego who happens to likekilling women.
极度自负 碰巧喜欢杀女人
Well,you had metill that last part... agent gideon.
除了最后那部分你都说对了 Gideon探员
Imagine how shockedI am, considering I haven'tdone anything.
想想我有多震惊 因为我什么都没做
I see a woman whoI think is in distressin the woodsand I get...
我在树林里看到一个女人 以为她处于危难中..
pounced on.
我就扑了过去
Fbi wantsto interview you. Talk about your work.
FBI想见你 谈谈你的作品
We never believed we'dhave you in custody.
我们没想到会是你被拘留
I mean,definitelythought the hollow man would be easierto catch.
我们的确以为空心人更容易被抓到
Is that upsetting?
很沮丧吧?
I thought the twoof you were friends, that you admired eachother's work and...
我想你们两个是朋友 你们钦佩彼此的作品
I don't knowthe hollow man.
我不认识空心人
But if I did,I'd say he sounds like an obsessed fan.
如果我认识 我会说他象是个讨厌的追随者
Is that howyou see yourself, as somebody famous?
你就是这么看自己的吗 以为自己很出名?
Well,from what I've read about the mill creek killer,I'd say he's an artist.
我读过的关于磨溪杀手的事情 我得说他像个艺术家
Fascination wasn'tcompletely one-sided.
迷恋不完全是单方面的
You did respondto his ads in the paper.
你回应了他在报纸上的广告
No one can respectwhat the hollow man has done.
没人会尊重空心人做的事
He's got no imagination.
他根本没有想象力
But he's smart.
但他很聪明
Foundmeredith dale's body, even toldthe media about it.
找到了Meredith Dale的尸体 还告诉了媒体
Whoever taught him, taught him very well.
不管是谁教了他 都教得很好
That's very true.
的确如此
It just soundslike the student turnson the teacher.
看起来学生反击了老师
No,no. He wasprotecting him.
不 不 他在保护那个人
Is that what you think the hollow manwas doing?
你觉得这就是空心人做的?
Well,what elsecould it be?
还能有什么?
Manipulating you, gaining your trust.
巧妙地利用你 得到你的信任
When he got it, the hollow manset you up.
得到之后 他就设计你
You werefront page newS. Now you'd be a footnote.
你曾是头版新闻 现在就要成为注脚了
Hollow man's out there,you're in here. It's all because of him.
空心人在外面 你却在这 全是因为他
Is that what you want?
这就是你想的吗?
You want meto get angry to help you catch him?
你想让我生气 然后就会帮你们抓他?
That is notyour problem,sir.
那不是你的问题 先生
Then what do you want?
那你想要什么?
I have just have one question.
我只有一个问题
If killing those womenmade you an artist, the thingsyou did to them afterthey were dead...
如果杀掉那些女人能使你成为艺术家 那么他们死后你做的事
what does that make you?
又能让你成为什么呢?
I mean,really it...
我是说 那真的
it just doesn't seemvery artistic,does it?
那看起来可不怎么像艺术家是吧?
You went back,you fix their make-up, you'd comb their hair.
你回去给他们化妆 梳头
And you visited them...
然后你去看他们
- over and over and over. - I didn't do that.
- 一遍又一遍 - 我没那么干过
If you thoughtyou were famous before, wait until the pressgets a hold of you--
如果以前你认为自己很出名 那么等着看媒体抓住你时会怎么样吧...
- you shut your mouth. - Details of your visit.
- 你住嘴 - 关于你探访的细节
Shut your mouth. I never went back.
闭嘴 我从没回去过
You expect meto believe that you onlykilled those women?
你指望我相信你只是杀了她们?
That it wasn'tyou who kept visitingthe corpses?
你没有一遍遍地参观那些尸体?
We foundlipstick in your hand when we caught you.
我们抓到你的时候 你手里握着一管唇膏
- You will nottell anyone that. - Excuse me?
- 别告诉别人 - 对不起?
I said you cannever say that.
我说你不能那么说
- You didn't visitthe corpses? - No.
- 你没去参观那些尸体? - 没有
- No,you justkilled them. - Yes.
- 没有 你只是杀了她们 - 是的
Yes. I killed them.
是的 我杀了她们
But...but you can'ttell anyone... that I went back.
但...但你不能再说...我回去过
You can't do that.
你不能那么做
The women of st.Louiscan rest easy tonight...
今晚St. Louiscan的妇女们可以放心休息了
after a long year,the mill creek killeris in custody.
磨溪杀手经过漫长的一年终于抓捕在案
This manis highly intelligent and he usesa sophisticated rouse
此人智商极高 他使用极其狡猾的手段
when luring these womenin public places.
在公共场合引诱那些妇女
The mill creek killeris someone the bauwill want to study
磨溪杀手是BAU值得学习的案例
as one of the mostcomplex criminals we've dealt with in years.
他是我们多年来所处理过的最复杂的罪犯
- Questions? - Yes?
- 有问题吗? - 请说
What's the fbi doingabout the other serial killer?
关于另一个杀手FBI将如何行动?
We have new information about that case.
关于那个案子我们有些新的消息
We no longerbelieve the shootingsare related.
我们不再认为枪击是有关联的
- Yes? - What's the new information?
- 请说 - 什么新消息?
We believe they areisolated incidents,
我们认为是孤立的个案
and we're lookinginto the possibility that the last 2were copycats.
我们在求证最后两起案件为模仿的可能性
Jim meyers?
Jim meyers?
Are you referringto the killer who callshimself the hollow man?
你是指那位称自己为空心人的杀手吗?
We believe the personwho wrote that letteris nothingbut a street thug.
我们认为写信的人只是个街头暴徒
We have evidencethat indicates that the letterwas just a prank
有证据显示那封信只是恶作剧
to throw us offthe investigation of the mill creek killer.
试图将我们从磨溪杀手的调查中引开
This is no longera bau case.
这将不再是BAU的案子
It lacks a certainsophistication,class, there'sjust nothing elegantabout it.
它缺乏复杂性 不够品味 没有任何值得一提的地方
That's all the questions we'll take for now.Thank you.
提问结束 谢谢
Well,we set the bait, we'll seeif he takes it.
我们放了饵 就看他是不是上钩了
Place your coins,keys, belts in the basket.
请把硬币 钥匙 皮带放进篮子里
Walk this way.
这边走
Stepto the side,please.
请到一边来
Extend your arms.
伸开双臂
Stay down.
趴着
give your weaponright now.
把你的武器给我 快点
Get up.
站起来
Where is he? I wantto see him right now.
他在哪? 我要马上见他
You tell himthe hollow man's here.
告诉他空心人在这里
He told youto say those things about me,didn't he?
他教你那么说我的是吗?
He told youto use those words.
他教你说那些话
Get him out of here.
把他带出去
I'm no lesselegant than he is.
我不比他差
- I'm no copycat. - Shut your mouth.
- 我不是模仿 - 闭嘴
I left youthe newspaper! I gave youthe mill creek killer!
我给你留下了报纸 我把磨溪杀手交给了你
What elsedo I have to do?
我还要做什么?
Go! Get him out of here!
快走! 带他离开这!
This is the storyfor tomorrow.
这是明天的新闻
"they were our daughters, sisters,brothers,and friends."
"他们曾是我们的女儿 姐妹 兄弟和朋友"
they have every rightto be remembered... and memorialized.
"他们应被我们回忆和缅怀..."
*There are nonewho live downtown...*
*There are none who live downtown...*
they didn't mentionthe shooter.
没有提到枪手
He was a nobody whowanted to be somebody by killing people andthey didn't give him that.
他曾默默无闻 想靠杀人出名 但人们不会让他得逞的
Good.
好极了
Mahatma gandhi once said,"remember that allthrough historythere have been tyrants and murderers
圣雄甘地曾说过"请记住 历史上那些暴君和凶手
and for a timethey seem invincible..."
曾有一度战无不胜..."
*like ancient bruises...*
*like ancient bruises...*
"but in the end,they always fall. Always."
"但最终他们全部都倒下了 永远如此"
*I'm awake to feel...*
*I'm awake to feel...*
please tell meyou haven't been there for the last 4 days.
别告诉我你在这呆了四天
I heard you wereflying back tonight.
我听说今晚你飞回来
Heard?How couldyou have heard a thing like that?
听说?你怎么可能听说这种事?
This was dropped offtoday.
这是今天送来的
I appreciateyour interest,agent, but profilingis a specialty.
我感谢你对此有兴趣 探员 但犯罪描述是个专业
We can't just letanyone who wants togive it a whirl.
我们不能让随便什么人都来尝试
The I-80 killer? Co-eds in indiana?
I-80杀手? 印地安那的女生?
Yes,I read iton the plane.
是的 我在飞机上看过了
They aren'tblitz attacks. This guy's organized.
他们不是闪电战 他们是有组织的
He's a white male,early 30s, and a smooth talker,
他是白人男性 30出头 很会讲话
because evenafter 11 victims, he can still convince
因为在有了11个受害人之后 他还能说服
educated women who know there's a predator out thereto get into his car.
那些受过教育的妇女 在她们知道外面有个凶残的杀手时 还坐进他的车里
How would youadvise the police?
你会怎么建议警察?
I would stake outthe ranch house, a night club in gary.
我会密切注意那个单层的房子 Gary的夜总会
They have a very popular ladies night on thursdays.
周四那有个非常受欢迎的女士之夜
If you look closely,you'll see that 8 outof the 11 victimswent missingon a friday morning.
如果你仔细看 会发现11名受害者中 有8个是在周五早上失踪的
So something gets this creep's motor runningon thursdays.
所以这个坏蛋在周四就开始行动了
This isn't a whirl,agent hotchner.
这不是尝试 Hotchner探员
I don't know how thepaperwork got screwed up
我不知道那些个人资料怎么乱写的
or maybe youbelieve my parents pulled some strings,which they didn't,by the way.
或是你觉得我父母做了什么手脚 顺便说 他们没有
I belong in this unit.
我应归于这个团队
And all I'masking you for is the chanceto show you that.
我只要求给我机会表现出来
I still needto look into this. I'm notpromising anything.
我还会继续观察 我不能承诺什么
Understood.
明白
We brief new cases every morning at 10:00 am.
我们每天早10点会对新案子做简报
You can see facilities management about a desk.
你可以找总务申请一张桌子
You won't be sorry.
你不会后悔的